MAHIMA RAO

619-630-7421 | mahiima.rao@gmail.com | Los Angeles, California <u>LINKEDIN</u> | <u>GITHUB</u>

SUMMARY

I'm a full stack developer proficient in React, Node JS, Express, Ruby, Javascript, HTML, CSS and Adobe suite. Before this, I worked with a non-profit organization as an urban designer iterating through a design idea to revitalize a river side low-income zone. I have worked with city of Phoenix to integrate and improve public transportation. I'm currently working on building a React app which facilitates easy resume writing. The app has login features with authentication for password.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MERN stack [MongoDB, Express, React Node JS], HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Ruby on Rails, SQL, APIs(Google maps, Open weather), Adobe suite, CAD, Sketchup

PROJECTS

Résumé writer

This app, which is still in development stage, is built using React framework for front-end and Node js for back-end using jwt web tokens for authentication and password hashing. A user can choose between 4 pre-designed templates to write a résumé without the worry of indentations and font sizes.

Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, React, Node JS, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Semantic-react, Heroku cloud platform to deploy app and Mlab for data storage.

Vacation Finder

This app was built by a team of developers. It is a crowdsourced image platform which allows you to login and add or search for locations that you might be interested in visiting. It also comes with location on map (using google maps API) and weather details (using open weather API).

Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, Node JS, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Heroku, MLab.

To try it out use the following credentials - username: vacationfinder@gmail.com

doctriatric : vacationini laci (agrillan

password: vacatlonFinder

The Cookbook

The focus of this project was to give users a platform to share their recipes. The app was built entirely using Ruby on Rails implementing full CRUD with authentication for password protection.

Technologies used: Ruby on rails version (Ruby 2.5.0, Rails 5.1.5), Postgresql, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Heroku

Remastering Space Invaders

The entire game is written in HTML and designed with CSS and animated in JavaScript using jQuery. The intention was to keep the code simple and use concepts that constitute 'vanilla javascript'.

Technologies used: Javascript, Jquery, HTML, CSS, Adobe Photoshop CS6

EXPERIENCE

ASIA INITIATIVES, Urban Design Researcher

Jan 2014 to Jun 2016

- Developed urban design proposals for restoration of Vaigai River in Madurai, India.
- Helped design the SoCCs (Social Capital Credits) system to incentivize riverside communities to become custodians of the river and earn healthcare, education and skill empowerment in turn.

PHOENIX URBAN RESEARCH LAB, AZ, Project Manager

Jan 2012 to Apr 2012

- Created a comprehensive mapping for TOD (Transit Oriented Development) for the city of Phoenix.
- Authored a historic mapping system for downtown Phoenix.

Designer

Apr 2011 to Dec 2011

- Pioneered Phoenix TOD (Transit Oriented Development) corridor map in GIS for use by over 500 ASU students and faculty alike.
- Designed mixed-use infill prototypes for Phoenix transit corridor to forecast light rail ridership and real estate impact.

CHENNAI CITY CONNECT Chennai, India, Consulting Architect

Mar 2009 to Sep 2009

- Redesigned street vendor-occupied spaces on high-traffic sidewalk in Chennai, to reduce pedestrian-related accidents by 30%
- Created centralized parking design for Chennai's busiest shopping district to reduce traffic congestion significantly
- Compiled bicycle awareness handbook to educate bicyclists, potentially increasing bicycle use for commuting

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive Jan 2018 to Apr 2018

Arizona State University

Master of Urban Design Aug 2010 to May 2012

Sushant School of Architecture, India

Bachelor of Architecture July 2002 to May 2007